Eleftherios Kousourakis

Nationality: Greek/Luxembourgish





e.kousou@pm.me

Summary

Senior DevOps & Backend Engineer with 7 years of experience.

Strong expertise in architecting cloud solutions across regions with automatic failover in AWS & Azure. Focused on backend Microservices Oriented Architecture and High Availability Systems.

Technical Skills

Languages C# (.NET), Java (Spring), Scala, Bash, Powershell, Groovy, Python, Kotlin **DevOps Terraform,** Terragrunt, **Ansible**, Azure Pipelines, Jenkins, Github Actions

AMQP, MQTT, STOMP, WebSockets Messaging

NoSQL DynamoDB, Elasticsearch

RDBMS MySQL, Postgres, MariaDB, SQL Server

Professional Experience

Kubernetes, Docker, Tomcat, Vagrant

Senior DevOps & Backend Engineer - Arhs Cube

May 2021 - Present

Virtualization

- Architect and provision multiple and on demand environments using Terraform, Terragrunt in Azure.
- Setup end to end release process to production, code scanning and CI/CD using Azure pipelines to ensure quality deliverables.
- Develop features to deliver complex business logic using C#, .NET 6 and EF6 and Azure Functions.
- Train and support team for best development process, git and release practices.

DevOps & Backend Engineer - CarpayDiem

2020 - 2021

- Architect & Migrate microservices from on premises servers to the cloud using AWS and Kubernetes
- Provision reproducible cloud environments using Terraform
- Work closely with the team to improve development processes (PR review, TTD, Code formatting etc.)

DevOps & Backend Engineer - Airboxlab

2016 - 2020

- Develop REST APIs, based on microservices pattern (50+ services), with API Gateway, dynamic documentation, stateless authentication
- Design & develop remote Linux system with priority on robustness and accessibility. (Systemd, Debian, Zabbix, fluentd, AWS S3)
- Expertise in infrastructure formation from scratch with focus on high availability, fault tolerance and monitoring, Emphasis on Infrastructure as Code methodology, (Docker, Ansible, Zabbix, ELK, AWS)
- Continuous deployment pipeline for 3 datacenters, ensuring zero down time, using containers and dynamic service discovery (Docker, AWS ECS, Consul, Jenkins, Git)
- Pub/Sub messaging for internal & external usage worldwide (RabbitMQ, MQTT, STOMP, AMQP)

Education

B.Sc. in Electronic Computer Systems Engineering - University of West Attica, Greece

4 years

French - Institut National des Langues, Luxembourg

2016 - Present

Luxembourgish - Institut National des Langues, Luxembourg

2018 - 2020

Running Containers on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service - Fast-Lane, Online

4 Days Training

Languages

Greek (native), English (C2, 7 years professional experience), French (B2), Luxembourgish (B1), German (A2).

Personal Interests

IT & Software Security, Open Source Software & Devops Conferences (Devops Days, All systems Go, Fossdem etc.), Krav Maga & Snowboarding